<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>NumFOCUS Foundation</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/</id><updated>2013-07-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Share your stories of how you use NumFOCUS supported tools</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/share-your-stories-of-how-you-use-numfocus-supported-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-07-12:share-your-stories-of-how-you-use-numfocus-supported-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read how others are you the tools NumFOCUS supports in  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/user-stories/"&gt;User Stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the community know how you&amp;#8217;re using the tools NumFOCUS supports. &amp;nbsp;Send your stories to: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/user-stories/"&gt;http://numfocus.org/user-stories/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Jobs</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/jobs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-07-06:jobs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Send Job Board listings to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;NumFOCUS.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;NumFOCUS.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Donations</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/donations.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-07-05:donations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS is a 501(c)3 nonprofit in the United States. Your tax deductible
donations go towards funding the following&amp;nbsp;activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsor sprints and&amp;nbsp;conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide scholarships and&amp;nbsp;grants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide hardware grants for student&amp;nbsp;developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay for the creation of publicly-available documentation and basic course&amp;nbsp;development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with domain-specific&amp;nbsp;organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raise funds from industries using Python and&amp;nbsp;NumPy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Contact</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/contact.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-07-04:contact.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Email should be send to:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:admin&amp;#64;numfocus.org"&gt;admin&amp;#64;numfocus.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Please address written correspondance to:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;NumFOCUS&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;P.O.&lt;/span&gt; Box 90596&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Austin, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TX&lt;/span&gt; 78709&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Fiscal Sponsorship</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/fiscal-sponsorship.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-30T20:21:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-30:fiscal-sponsorship.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In our efforts to promote and support high-level languages, reproducible scientific research
and open-source development, we are proud to announce that our Fiscal Sponsorship
program is now&amp;nbsp;underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiscal Sponsorship is a an arrangement between a 501(c)(3) public
charity and a project (that does not have that tax status) in which,
typically, the charity receives and expends funds to advance the
charitable work of the project while retaining discretion and control
over the funds.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;-Eric Gorovitz, associate, Adler &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Colvin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our Fiscal Sponsorship program, the nonexempt project must act so as
to further the exempt purposes of&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please look over our Fiscal Sponsorship Agreement and let us know if you
have questions or would like additional information by contacting us at:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;numfocus.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;numfocus.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fiscal-sponsorship-agreement"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fiscal Sponsorship&amp;nbsp;Agreement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the source for our fiscal sponsorship document &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/numfocus/fiscal-sponsorship"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Feel free to leave comments, feedback, or issue pull&amp;nbsp;requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Board</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:board.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="board-of-directors"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Board of&amp;nbsp;Directors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ralf-gommers"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ralf&amp;nbsp;Gommers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ralf Gomers" src="static/images/portrait_rgommers.jpg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf Gommers received his PhD in physics from University College London and did
his post-doctoral work at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, working in the field of experimental atomic
physics. After a short period working on electronics for Magnetic Resonance
Imaging devices at Philips Research, he is now a designer for advanced
lithography machines at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASML&lt;/span&gt; in the Netherlands. During his post-doctoral work
he became involved in the SciPy community. He is an active contributor to
NumPy, SciPy and statsmodels, and has also contributed to scikit-image. Ralf
has been the NumPy release manager for two years, and is currently the SciPy
release&amp;nbsp;manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="emmanuelle-gouillart"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Emmanuelle&amp;nbsp;Gouillart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Emmanuelle Gouillart" src="static/images/emma_python_smaller.jpg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emmanuelle Gouillart works as a physics researcher in the joint laboratory
between the French National Research Center (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNRS&lt;/span&gt;), and the French corporation
Saint-Gobain. She holds a physics PhD from the Université Pierre et Marie
Curie, and an MSc from the Ecole Normale Supérieure in Paris. Her research
interests are in glass melting, tomography imaging, and fluid mixing.
Scientific Python is the ubiquitous tool in her daily&amp;nbsp;research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She became involved in the Scientific Python community with the Numpy/Scipy
documentation marathon from 2008 on, and shortly after she started teaching
Scientific Python during the Python African Tour event in Dakar in 2009. She
has been contributing to the Scipy Lecture Notes used for the Euroscipy
tutorial sessions since Euroscipy 2010, where she was tutorial chair, and she
has organized several training sessions on Scientific Python since then. She
has been part of the organizing board of the Euroscipy conferences in 2010,
2011 and 2012. Her daily use of image processing has led her to become a
regular contributor to the Python&amp;nbsp;scikit-image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="perry-greenfield"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Perry&amp;nbsp;Greenfield&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Perry Greenfield" src="static/images/perry-greenfield.jpg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perry Greenfield received a Ph.D. in Physics from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;M.I.T.&lt;/span&gt; His thesis was based
on Very Large Array radio observations of the first discovered gravitational
lens. After a short stint in communications engineering at Bell Labs, he ended
up at the Space Telescope Science Institute, where he has worked for the last
26 years. He initially was responsible for calibrating the Faint Object Camera
for the Hubble Space Telescope, but for the last 16 years he has been
leading the Science Software Branch. He has pioneered the use of Python in
astronomy, and his group has been heavily involved in Python for the last 12
years. They have developed PyRAF, numarray (the precursor to current NumPy
capabilities), PyFITS, and been heavily involved in the development and
support of matplotlib. His group is now heavily involved in developing the
science software to support the next large space telescope under
construction, the James Webb Space&amp;nbsp;Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="jarrod-millman"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Jarrod&amp;nbsp;Millman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Jarrod Millman" src="static/images/jarrod-millman-150x150.png" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarrod Millman is on the SciPy steering committee and a contributor to both the
NumPy and SciPy projects. While director of computing for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UC&lt;/span&gt; Berkeley’s
Neuroscience Institute, he helped found the Neuroimaging in Python (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIPY&lt;/span&gt;)
project. Currently, he is a software developer at Berkeley’s Brain Imaging&amp;nbsp;Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="travis-oliphant"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travis&amp;nbsp;Oliphant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Travis Oliphant" src="static/images/Travis_Oliphant.gif" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Oliphant has a Ph.D. in Biomedical Engineering from the Mayo Clinic, and
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;M.S.&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;B.S.&lt;/span&gt; degrees in Electrical Engineering (and Math) from Brigham Young
University. Travis has worked extensively with Python for numerical and
scientific programming since 1997, and was the primary developer of the NumPy
package and the author of the definitive Guide to NumPy. He is also the primary
founding author of the SciPy package. During his academic career, he has worked
in the fields of satellite remote sensing, Magnetic Resonance Imaging (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MRI&lt;/span&gt;),
Ultrasound, elastography, and general inverse&amp;nbsp;problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was an Assistant Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Brigham
Young University from 2001 to 2007 where he taught courses in probability
theory, electromagnetics, inverse problems, and signal processing. In addition,
he directed the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BYU&lt;/span&gt; Biomedical Imaging Lab, and performed research on scanning
impedance imaging. He has done consulting work since 1997 in laser scattering
off of semiconductors, sparse matrix calculations for search engines, and mesh
transformations for fluid&amp;nbsp;dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Oliphant served as President of Enthought from 2007 until 2011, where he
oversaw the establishment of additional satellite offices in New York City,
Belgium, Cambridge &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;, and Mumbai, India. During this time, he worked with
Fortune 50 companies such as Shell, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J.P.&lt;/span&gt; Morgan, and Proctor and Gamble in all
aspects of the contractual relationship – from contracts to training to code
architecture and code development. He also served on the Board of Directors for
Enthought from 2008 until 2011, and during that time, formed strong connections
with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J.P.&lt;/span&gt; Morgan technical leadership staff and other industry&amp;nbsp;leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fernando-perez"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fernando&amp;nbsp;Pérez&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Fernando Pérez" src="static/images/fernando_perez.jpg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fernando Pérez received his PhD in theoretical physics from the University of
Colorado and did his post-doctoral work there in applied mathematics, working
on fast algorithms for partial differential equations. He is currently a
research scientist at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UC&lt;/span&gt; Berkeley’s Helen Wills Neuroscience Institute,
focusing on the development of new analysis methods for brain imaging problems
and high-level scientific computing tools.  Towards the end of his graduate
studies, he became involved with the development of Python tools for scientific
computing. He started the open source IPython project in 2001 when he needed an
efficient interactive workflow for everyday scientific tasks. He continues to
lead IPython, as part of a growing team of talented developers.  He remains
committed to the development of open, high-level tools to tackle the current
challenges in computationally-based scientific research and education across
disciplines. He is a member of the matplotlib development team and has
contributed to numpy, scipy, sympy, mayavi, nipy and nitime. He regularly
organizes workshops and lectures aimed at teaching the use of these tools to
audiences at levels ranging from high-school students to research scientists.
He is also a member of the Python Software Foundation.  When not glued to a
computer, Fernando tries to spend as much time as possible with his wife
outdoors hiking and backpacking, as well as climbing. For more information, see
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fperez.org"&gt;http://fperez.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="didrik-pinte"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Didrik&amp;nbsp;Pinte&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didrik Pinte has had a mixed career between academia
and the private sector. As a researcher, he focused his work on large scale
water allocation problems during 4 years at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCL&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium. After another 5 years
running his own consulting company in the field of environmental data
management systems, mostly based on Python, he joined Enthought. He is now
running the European operations of Enthought out of Cambridge,&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="anthony-scopatz-treasurer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anthony Scopatz&amp;nbsp;(Treasurer)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="Anthony Scopatz" src="static/images/scopatz_avatar-1.jpeg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scopatz.com/"&gt;Anthony Scopatz&lt;/a&gt; is a computational scientist and long
time Python developer, Anthony holds his &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BS&lt;/span&gt; in Physics from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UC&lt;/span&gt; Santa Barbara and
Ph.D. in Mechanical / Nuclear Engineering from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UT&lt;/span&gt; Austin. A former Enthought
employee, he spent his post-doctoral studies at the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FLASH&lt;/span&gt; Center at the University
of Chicago in the Astrophysics Department. He is currently a Staff Scientist at the
University of Wisconsin-Maidson in Engineering Physics.  Anthony’s research interests
revolve around essential physics modeling of the nuclear fuel cycle,
and information theory &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; entropy. Anthony has published and spoken at numerous
conferences on a variety of science &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; software development&amp;nbsp;topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="andy-terrel"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Andy&amp;nbsp;Terrel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/andy-terrel-portrait200px2.jpg" src="static/images/andy-terrel-portrait200px2.jpg" style="height: 150px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Terrel received his PhD in computer science at the University of Chicago
in 2010 and is currently a staff researcher at the Texas Advance Computing
Center at the Univerisity of Texas at Austin.  His major emphasis of research
has been on the automation of numerical methods on high performance computing
resources. To this end, he has provided numerous contributions to a wide
variety of open source projects, including the popular FEniCS project and&amp;nbsp;SymPy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Terrel has held roles at universities, government laboratories, and several
companies.  In all of these roles, Dr. Terrel has been an expert in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HPC&lt;/span&gt;
computing as well as an advocate for the open source software movement.  Dr.
Terrel has served as chair and organizer of many scientific computing
conferences including SciPy Conference, FEniCS Conference, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HPC&lt;/span&gt;^3, and
Scientific Software Days.  He is an active contributor and reviewer to several
scientific computing&amp;nbsp;journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>inSCIght</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/inscight.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:inscight.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="|filename|/images/InSciGHT.jpg" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/InSciGHT.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://inscight.org/"&gt;inSCIght&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast that focuses on scientific computing in all of its
various forms. We have four panelists engage head-to-head on poignant and
interesting topics. The panelists are drawn from all across the scientific
computing community.  From embedded systems experts to very high level language
gurus, from biologists to nuclear engineers, the hosts of inSCIght use
computers to solve science and engineering problems everyday. This podcast
throws people, ideas, and opinions into an audio-blender hoping to educate and
entice each other and the world.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://inscight.org/"&gt;http://inscight.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Projects</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="core-projects"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Core&amp;nbsp;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="numpy"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numpy.scipy.org/"&gt;NumPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/NumPY.png" src="static/images/NumPY.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumPy is the fundamental package needed for scientific computing with Python.
Besides its obvious scientific uses, NumPy can also be used as an efficient
multi-dimensional container of generic data. Arbitrary data-types can be
defined. This allows NumPy to seamlessly and speedily integrate with a wide
variety of databases.
Repositories for NumPy binaries:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/#numpy"&gt;http://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/#numpy&lt;/a&gt;,
a variety of versions - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/numpy/files/NumPy/"&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/numpy/files/NumPy/&lt;/a&gt;,
version 1.6.1 - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/numpy/files/NumPy/1.6.1/"&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/numpy/files/NumPy/1.6.1/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scipy"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scipy.org/"&gt;SciPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/scipy.png" src="static/images/scipy.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SciPy is open-source software for mathematics, science, and engineering. It is
also the name of a very popular conference on scientific programming with
Python. The SciPy library depends on NumPy, which provides convenient and fast
N-dimensional array manipulation. The SciPy library is built to work with NumPy
arrays, and provides many user-friendly and efficient numerical routines such
as routines for numerical integration and&amp;nbsp;optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="matplotlib"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://matplotlib.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/matplotlib.png" src="static/images/matplotlib.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2D plotting library for Python that produces high quality figures that can be
used in various hardcopy and interactive environments. matplolib is
compatiable with python scripts and the python and ipython&amp;nbsp;shells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ipython"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ipython.org/"&gt;IPython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/ipython.png" src="static/images/ipython.png" style="height: 70px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High quality open source python shell that includes tools for high level and
interactive parallel&amp;nbsp;computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sympy"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://SymPy.org/en/index.html"&gt;SymPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/SymPy2.jpg" src="static/images/SymPy2.jpg" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SymPy is a Python library for symbolic mathematics. It aims to become a
full-featured computer algebra system (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAS&lt;/span&gt;) while keeping the code as simple as
possible in order to be comprehensible and easily extensible. SymPy is written
entirely in Python and does not require any external&amp;nbsp;libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-projects"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other&amp;nbsp;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cython"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cython.org/"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/cython.png" src="static/images/cython.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cython is a language based on Pyrex that makes writing C extensions for Python
as easy as writing them in Python itself. Cython supports calling C functions
and declaring C types on variables and class attributes, allowing the compiler
to generate very efficient C code from Cython&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pandas"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pandas.pydata.org/"&gt;pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/pandas.png" src="static/images/pandas.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pandas is an open source, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt;-licensed library providing high-performance,
easy-to-use data structures and data analysis tools for the Python programming&amp;nbsp;language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pytables"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pytables.github.com/"&gt;PyTables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/logo-pytables-small.png" src="static/images/logo-pytables-small.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyTables is a package for managing hierarchical datasets and designed to
efficiently and easily cope with extremely large amounts of data. PyTables is
built on top of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDF5&lt;/span&gt; library, using the Python language and the NumPy
package. It features an Pythonic interface combined with C / Cython extensions
for the performance-critical parts of the code.  This makes it a fast, yet
extremely easy to use tool for very large amounts of data.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pytables.github.com/"&gt;http://pytables.github.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scikit-image"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scikit-image.org/"&gt;scikit-image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/scikitsimage.png" src="static/images/scikitsimage.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free high-quality and peer-reviewed volunteer produced collection of algorithms
for image&amp;nbsp;processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scikit-learn"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scikit-learn.org/stable/"&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/scikitslearn.png" src="static/images/scikitslearn.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Module designed for scientific pythons that provides accesible solutions to
machine learning&amp;nbsp;problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="scikits-statsmodels"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scikits.appspot.com/statsmodels"&gt;Scikits-Statsmodels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/scikits.png" src="static/images/scikits.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statsmodels is a Python package that provides a complement to scipy for
statistical computations including descriptive statistics and estimation of
statistical&amp;nbsp;models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="spyder"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/spyderlib/"&gt;Spyder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/spyder.png" src="static/images/spyder.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactive development environment for Python that features advanced editing,
interactive testing, debugging and introspection capabilities, as well as a
numerical computing environment made possible through the support of Ipython,
NumPy, SciPy, and&amp;nbsp;matplotlib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="theano"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://deeplearning.net/software/theano/#"&gt;Theano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/theano_logo_allblue_200x46.png" src="static/images/theano_logo_allblue_200x46.png" style="height: 50px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theano is a Python library that allows you to define, optimize, and evaluate
mathematical expressions involving multi-dimensional arrays&amp;nbsp;efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="associated-projects"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Associated&amp;nbsp;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS is currently looking for representatives to enable us to promote the
following projects.  For&amp;nbsp;information contact us at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;NumFOCUS.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;NumFOCUS.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sage"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sagemath.org/"&gt;Sage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/sage.png" src="static/images/sage.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source mathematics sofware system that combines existing open-source
packages into a Python-based&amp;nbsp;interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="networkx"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://networkx.lanl.gov/"&gt;NetworkX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NetworkX is a Python language software package for the creation, manipulation,
and study of the structure, dynamics, and functions of complex&amp;nbsp;networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-x-y"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/pythonxy/wiki/Welcome"&gt;Python(X,Y)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt="static/images/pythonxy.png" src="static/images/pythonxy.png" style="height: 75px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free scientific and engineering development software used for numerical
computations, and analysis and visualization of data using the Python
programmimg&amp;nbsp;language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python’s Use in Science</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/pythons-use-in-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:pythons-use-in-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Please send links to papers, blogs, articles, or announcements that show
Python&amp;#8217;s use in science to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;numfocus.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;numfocus.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SciPy 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/scipy-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:scipy-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://conference.scipy.org/scipy2013/index.php"&gt;SciPy 2013&lt;/a&gt;, the twelfth annual Scientific Computing with Python conference,
will be held June 24th - 29th in Austin, Texas.  The main conference themes are
Machine Learning &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Reproducible&amp;nbsp;Science.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Software Carpentry</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/software-carpentry.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-05-07:software-carpentry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="|filename|/images/software-carpentry-logo-285x58.png" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/software-carpentry-logo-285x58.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to help scientists be more productive by teaching them basic computing skills. Our approach combines short, intensive workshops with self-paced online instruction. The benefits are more reliable results and higher productivity: a day a week is common, and a ten-fold improvement isn’t rare.  For more information check out our blog at  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://software-carpentry.org/blog/"&gt;http://software-carpentry.org/blog/&lt;/a&gt;, follow us on twitter as  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/swcarpentry"&gt;&amp;#64;swcarpentry&lt;/a&gt;, or contact us by email at  &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;software-carpentry.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;software-carpentry.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>April 15, 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board-meeting-minutes2013-04-15s.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-04-15:board-meeting-minutes2013-04-15s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="participating"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Participating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf Gommers, Didrik Pinte, Anthony Scopatz, Leah Silen, Perry
Greenfield, Fernando Perez, Andy Terrel, Travis&amp;nbsp;Oliphant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not&amp;nbsp;attending&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emmanuelle Gouillart, Jarrod&amp;nbsp;Millman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="treasurers-report"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treasurer’s&amp;nbsp;Report&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have until May 15th to file our 990 forms for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IRS&lt;/span&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Didrik is
working on the European bank account, it’s moving&amp;nbsp;along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="old-business"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Old&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Proceeds from&amp;nbsp;PyData&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exact figure isn’t available yet, waiting for final checks from Santa
Clara Convention&amp;nbsp;Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Boot Camp for Women in Science and&amp;nbsp;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="team-reports"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team&amp;nbsp;Reports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundraising:&lt;/strong&gt; Ralf edited the fellowship&amp;nbsp;document&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Have until May 15th to file 990 form with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IRS&lt;/span&gt;.
&amp;nbsp;Didrik will report next call with more concrete details on opening a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;
bank&amp;nbsp;account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-business"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;New&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For next week, take some time to think about what the corporate
sponsorship levels are and what they mean. &amp;nbsp;We need a more solid
business model here. &amp;nbsp;Look at the Van Lindberg email from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PSF&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fiscal-sponsorship"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fiscal&amp;nbsp;Sponsorship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establishment of rules for projects to have formal relationship with&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsorship is in the public&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ping Tony about fiscal&amp;nbsp;council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Call for Speakers</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/call-for-speakers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-04-07:call-for-speakers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers for PyData Boston (July 27-28th) is now open. If you are
interested in presenting a talk on how you use Python for data management,
analytics, or visualization or leading a tutorial session, please email a short
description of your idea, including whether it is a beginner or advanced
presentation, to &lt;a class="reference external" href="boston_proposals&amp;#64;pydata.org"&gt;boston_proposals&amp;#64;pydata.org&lt;/a&gt;. The initial call-for-speakers for
PyData Boston will be open through May&amp;nbsp;31st.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>April 1, 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board-meeting-minutes2013-04-01.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-04-01:board-meeting-minutes2013-04-01.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="participating"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Participating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy R. Terrel, Ralf Gommers, Fernando Perez, Didrik Pinte, Anthony
Scopatz, Leah Silen, Travis&amp;nbsp;Oliphant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not&amp;nbsp;attending&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarrod Millman, Emmanuelle Gouillart, &amp;nbsp;Perry&amp;nbsp;Greenfield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="treasurers-report"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treasurer’s&amp;nbsp;Report&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SciPy’13 has been officially sponsored, funds for this were disbursed
($2500). &amp;nbsp;This gives Numfocus a silver sponsor level (2 passes, booth,
name on website). &amp;nbsp;Once the corresponding details for EuroScipy are
clear, the same will be&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mac Mini - Is this ready to be publicized on the&amp;nbsp;site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf reports that Christoph hasn’t replied much to his queries. &amp;nbsp;The
site is up and a NumPy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CI&lt;/span&gt; engine is set up, but he’s waiting for
responses from Christoph. &amp;nbsp;Anthony suggests asking the list for help so
that someone can support&amp;nbsp;Christoph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fundraising for Boot Camp for Women in Science and&amp;nbsp;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is ongoing with a funder to secure the majority of the cost. &amp;nbsp;More
follow-up is&amp;nbsp;needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsorship of SciPy and&amp;nbsp;passes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our donations are earmarked for student support, we get two
session/tutorial passes at the silver sponsor level (see Treasurer’s
report for&amp;nbsp;details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;SciPy domains ready to&amp;nbsp;transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis checked that all domains have been transferred. &amp;nbsp;We will wait for
the person working on SciPy central before pointing the domains over to
a new&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="team-reports"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team&amp;nbsp;Reports&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership:&lt;/strong&gt; we are considering opening up the membership model to
one where the basic level is free for anyone to join, and the
paying/participating membership levels have some benefits as well. &amp;nbsp;We
will draft some language on this topic in the coming&amp;nbsp;weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundraising:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ralf and Andy proposed updating the language on the
Technical Fellowship to: “Purpose (new formulation): The purpose of the
NumFOCUS Technology Fellowship Program is to enable high-potential
graduate students and early career professionals to work full-time on
cutting-edge scientific open source&amp;nbsp;software.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Target areas: infrastructure for SciPy eco-system, accessible and
reproducible computing (&amp;amp; core&amp;nbsp;projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis likes the intent. Keeping the educational component in mind is&amp;nbsp;important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publicity/Promotion:&lt;/strong&gt; Andy manned the booth at PyCon along with Leah
and Anthony. &amp;nbsp;Lots of contacts were made, there was good interest and a
number of people came by with the idea of doing “bounties” on specific
topics. &amp;nbsp;Some people didn’t like the nomination model for membership.
&amp;nbsp;Talked to the Center for Open Science, a new venture at the University
of Virginia (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://centerforopenscience.org/"&gt;http://centerforopenscience.org&lt;/a&gt;) whose goals are very
well aligned with NumFOCUS. &amp;nbsp;Anthony also talked to the “Data science
for social good” group in Chicago, which has an explicit education and
open government/open science mission; they have a 10-week summer
fellowship program we can learn&amp;nbsp;from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Target areas: infrastructure for SciPy eco-system, accessible and reproducible computing (&amp;amp; core&amp;nbsp;projects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis likes the intent. Keeping the educational component in mind is&amp;nbsp;important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publicity/Promotion&lt;/strong&gt; Andy manned the booth at PyCon along with Leah and Anthony.  Lots of contacts were made, there was good interest and a number of people came by with the idea of doing “bounties” on specific topics.  Some people didn’t like the nomination model for membership.  Talked to the Center for Open Science, a new venture at the University of Virginia (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://centerforopenscience.org"&gt;http://centerforopenscience.org&lt;/a&gt;) whose goals are very well aligned with NumFOCUS.  Anthony also talked to the “Data science for social good” group in Chicago, which has an explicit education and open government/open science mission; they have a 10-week summer fellowship program we can learn&amp;nbsp;from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grants/Fellowships&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UQ&lt;/span&gt; Foundation update from&amp;nbsp;PyCon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Euro SciPy sponsorship - Participant&amp;nbsp;Sponsor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. &amp;nbsp;Disco domain and trademark transfer to NumFOCUS from Nokia, Ville&amp;nbsp;Tuulos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Disco authors have left Nokia and would like to have numfocus to
hold that domain as well as their trademark and all other &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; associated
with the project. &amp;nbsp;They are waiting to see our domain transfer form.
&amp;nbsp;Anthony asked about what legal responsibilities we’d be exposed to in
terms of defending the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. &amp;nbsp;Industry funding for IPython - contract issues. Conversation with
Brad Kuhn from the Software Conservancy. &amp;nbsp;Fernando will set up a
conversation with Brad Kuhn and any board members who are interested in
participating, to clarify some of the legal issues involved. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SWC&lt;/span&gt; has
experience with this and Brad offered to provide some information to&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. &amp;nbsp;PyData Vimeo Channel - $150 to $200. The motion for these funds was&amp;nbsp;approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Joining NumFOCUS</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/membership.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-03-13:membership.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="becoming-a-member-of-numfocus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Becoming a Member of&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year the NumFOCUS Foundation was formed to &amp;#8220;promote the use of
accessible and reproducible computing in science and technology.&amp;#8221; Much
of this effort centers around the use of Python and it’s&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS is excited to announce membership is now open. The involvement of the
community is vital in helping to help raise the visibility of Python and its
advantages within the scientific and engineering community, as well as to
support and promote its&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples of the numerous ways members can become involved&amp;nbsp;include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joining committees and teams formed to help further the goals of&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping to build a system to keep track of scientific and engineering
publications making significant use of Python, while helping to document its
importance in these&amp;nbsp;fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocating the use of Python by recording and publicizing success stories of
researchers and companies who use&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitating events at conferences, workshops, and sprints that educate
attendees regarding the advantages of using Python in technical&amp;nbsp;areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping with the selection of individuals and organizations to receive
financial support for conferences, workshops, and&amp;nbsp;fellowships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggesting and assisting in the formation of&amp;nbsp;committees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other advantages of membership&amp;nbsp;include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% Discount on PyData&amp;nbsp;conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounts on products - 20% off&amp;nbsp;IOPro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking with others in the scientific and engineering Python&amp;nbsp;community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chance to have greater insight into NumFOCUS and to influence its&amp;nbsp;work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunity to highlight one’s personal or corporate involvement with
the&amp;nbsp;foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership&amp;nbsp;Fees:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$128&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Professional (&amp;lt;5 years work experience):&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$64&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student or Retired:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;$32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corporations: Fees are dependent on number of employees, see website for&amp;nbsp;details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="to-apply"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To&amp;nbsp;Apply&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit the following information to:&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;numfocus.org"&gt;info&amp;#64;numfocus.org&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;You
will be notified by email regarding status and membership&amp;nbsp;fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Bio or&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Statement of support of&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Name of member who invited you (Invitations are not required at this&amp;nbsp;time)*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Women in Technology Initiatives</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/boot-camp-for-women-in-science-engineering.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-26T17:58:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-02-26:boot-camp-for-women-in-science-engineering.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="women-in-science-engineering-boot-camps"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Women in Science &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Engineering Boot&amp;nbsp;Camps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 24-25 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/"&gt;NumFOCUS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://software-carpentry.org/"&gt;Software Carpentry&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;are hosting a
software skills boot camp for 120 women in science and engineering at
Microsoft Research in Boston. We are seeking sponsorship from companies
and others who would like to support our efforts to hold similar boot
camps in other&amp;nbsp;locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-a-boot-camp"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a Boot&amp;nbsp;Camp?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two-day workshops teach scientists how to write, test and manage
research software. Topics covered include the Unix shell, version
control, basic Python programming, testing, and debugging Boot camps are
example-driven and alternate short tutorials with hands-on practical
exercises. Since learners work on their own laptops, they leave with a
set of working tools they can use immediately to increase their
productivity and improve confidence in their&amp;nbsp;results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-the-funding-for"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is the Funding&amp;nbsp;For?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS and Software Carpentry are non-profit organizations, and all of
our instructors are volunteers. Donations to the Boot Camp for Women
will cover the cost of travel and lodging for instructors, as well as
incidental expenses such as&amp;nbsp;refreshments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-can-i-contribute"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How Can I&amp;nbsp;Contribute?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PayPal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google&amp;nbsp;Checkout&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align: middle;"&gt;
&lt;form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post"&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align: middle;"&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;// &lt; ![CDATA[&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;function validateAmount(amount){&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
    if(amount.value.match( /^[0-9]+(\.([0-9]+))?$/)){&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
        return true;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
    }else{&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
        alert('You must enter a valid donation.');&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
        amount.focus();&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
        return false;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
    }&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
}&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
// ]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;form id="BB_BuyButtonForm" action="https://checkout.google.com/cws/v2/Donations/112611646391039/checkoutForm" method="post" name="BB_BuyButtonForm" target="_top" onsubmit="return validateAmount(this.item_price_1)"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="60%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="40%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suggested minimum donation:&amp;nbsp;$10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="women-in-technology-workshops"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Women in Technology&amp;nbsp;Workshops&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These half-day events will be presented by NumFOCUS and held in
conjunction with certain PyData conferences. &amp;nbsp;The first workshop will be
held in the fall at PyData &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NYC&lt;/span&gt;. More information coming&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Current Fundraising Efforts:</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/numfocus-is-currently-raising-funds-for-the-following.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-26T16:36:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-02-26:numfocus-is-currently-raising-funds-for-the-following.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="boot-camp-for-women-in-science-engineering"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Boot Camp for Women in Science &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted by Software Carpentry and&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 24-25&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/"&gt;NumFOCUS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.software-carpentry.org"&gt;Software Carpentry&lt;/a&gt; are hosting a software skills boot camp in Boston for 120 women in science and engineering. We are seeking sponsorship from companies and others who would like to help support our efforts to hold similar events in other&amp;nbsp;locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/numfocus-is-currently-raising-funds-for-the-following/boot-camp-for-women-in-science-engineering/"&gt;**For More&amp;nbsp;Information**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a&amp;nbsp;Donation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;
 &lt;em&gt;PayPal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google&amp;nbsp;Checkout&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align: middle;"&gt;
&lt;form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post"&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align: middle;"&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;// &lt; ![CDATA[&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
function validateAmount(amount){    if(amount.value.match( /^[0-9]+(\.([0-9]+))?$/)){       return true;    }else{      alert('You must enter a valid donation.');      amount.focus();         return false;   } }&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
// ]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form id="BB_BuyButtonForm" action="https://checkout.google.com/cws/v2/Donations/112611646391039/checkoutForm" method="post" name="BB_BuyButtonForm" target="_top" onsubmit="return validateAmount(this.item_price_1)"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="60%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="40%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;$&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suggested minimum donation:&amp;nbsp;$10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="john-hunter-technical-fellowship"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;John Hunter Technical&amp;nbsp;Fellowship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now accepting donations to fund the John Hunter Technical&amp;nbsp;Fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This educational program furthers our mission, as a public charity, to promote
the use of accessible and reproducible computing in science and open-source&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the NumFOCUS Technology Fellowship is to bridge the gap between
academia and real-world, open-source coding projects by providing a capstone
experience for individuals coming from a scientific educational&amp;nbsp;background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program consists of a 3-18 month project-based training program for
graduate students, postdoctoral scientists and early-career faculty. Fellows
work on actual open source software projects under the guidance of mentors who
are leading scientists and software engineers. &amp;nbsp;Collaboration with these top
industry developers enables scientists to develop specific skills needed to
contribute to cutting-edge open-source&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>February 4, 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board-meeting-minutes2013-02-04.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-02-04:board-meeting-minutes2013-02-04.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="participating"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Participating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leah Silen, Travis Oliphant, Anthony Scopatz, Ralf Gommers, Fernando
Perez, Andy R. Terrel, Perry Greenfield, Jarrod&amp;nbsp;Millman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Not&amp;nbsp;attending&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Prabhu Ramachandran, Emmanuelle&amp;nbsp;Gouillart&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="approval-of-prior-minutes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Approval of prior&amp;nbsp;minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior minutes have been&amp;nbsp;approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="old-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="boot-camp-for-women-in-science-and-engineering"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Boot Camp for Women in Science and&amp;nbsp;Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a Software Carpentry workshop, requesting $6,000. &amp;nbsp;This is a worthy
endeavor but beyond our ability to fund at that level. &amp;nbsp;We’d be happy to
contribute partially towards this goal (up to $1500) and help them with the
rest of the fundraising. &amp;nbsp;We will advertise this on the&amp;nbsp;website&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="update-on-christoph-deils-mac"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update on Christoph Deil’s&amp;nbsp;Mac&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac will be hosted in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, will be bought by Anthony from Apple and Leah
will ship it to the hosting company. &amp;nbsp;Once it’s up and running it will be
announced on the&amp;nbsp;list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="update-on-increasing-board-size"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update on increasing board&amp;nbsp;size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to report, Jarrod will follow-up this week? &amp;nbsp;No new activity on this,
Jarrod will report back on&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pygotham"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PyGotham&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community site run by Gloria W., essentially a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NYC&lt;/span&gt; PyCon. &amp;nbsp;Upon further
communication with her, it became clear that she had in mind a fair amount of
engagement which might go beyond the resources that Numfocus currently&amp;nbsp;has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony and Fernando express that it’s important to have a memo of
understanding, stating that the conference is nonprofit and that NumFOCUS
supports it with the idea of promoting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt; in Python. Should be checked that
there are no tax-related issues with handling this&amp;nbsp;money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="result-of-numpy-com-numpy-org-appraisal"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Result of numpy.com / numpy.org&amp;nbsp;appraisal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Turner donated these two domains, he’s getting this appraisal notice so
he can claim a tax deduction.  numpy.com: reported as worth $5850, the .org is
still&amp;nbsp;pending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="follow-up-by-andy-with-sloan-foundation-program-directors"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow up by Andy with Sloan Foundation program&amp;nbsp;directors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy wanted to know exactly what he should discuss with Sloan F. to avoid
bombarding them with too many things in parallel.  Andy asked about clarifying
how the budget would work for the technical fellowships. &amp;nbsp;After a fair amount
of back and forth on clarifying the intent of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TF&lt;/span&gt; idea, Jarrod, Andy and
Ralf planned to work further on making this more precise. &amp;nbsp;Andy mentioned the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSF&lt;/span&gt; Computing Innovation Fellows program (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cifellow.org/"&gt;http://cifellow.org/&lt;/a&gt;) (no longer
active) as well as Google Summer of Code
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developers.google.com/open-source/soc/"&gt;https://developers.google.com/open-source/soc/&lt;/a&gt;) as two ideas that we can
use to frame the&amp;nbsp;discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sloan is also interested in citation/impact reporting, at SciPy’12 there
was discussion about citation infrastructure for software. &amp;nbsp;The alt-metrics
community has done a lot of work on this, it might be useful to interface with
them. &amp;nbsp;Andy mentions that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSF&lt;/span&gt; just put out a Dear Colleague letter asking
about how to measure the impact of software, perhaps Numfocus could provide a
reply to&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="team-reports"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team&amp;nbsp;Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="membership"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to report, but Perry plans to start meetings to discuss&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fundraising"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fundraising&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversations with industry starting. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial Industry interested in
Technical&amp;nbsp;Fellowships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="publicity-promotion"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publicity/Promotion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to&amp;nbsp;report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grants-fellowships"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grants/Fellowships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to&amp;nbsp;report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finance"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to&amp;nbsp;report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="approved-minutes-are-now-on-the-website-under-board"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Approved minutes are now on the website under&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;Board&amp;#8221;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="numfocus-and-scipy-2013-conference"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NumFOCUS and SciPy 2013&amp;nbsp;conference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy &amp;nbsp;and Anthony are heavily involved with the organization of this year’s
SciPy conference, they will try to involve others from the board on this&amp;nbsp;effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="numpy-release-management-ondrej-certik"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NumPy release management (Ondrej Certik,&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8230;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy &amp;nbsp;and Anthony are heavily involved with the organization of this year’s
Ondrej is moving on to a postdoc position at Los Alamos. &amp;nbsp;He may be
able to do a bit more release management in the future, but it would be
ideal if the money came via NumFocus, since up until now it has been
done directly as Continuum. &amp;nbsp;Once that transition is done, Ondrej would
report directly to Numfocus. &amp;nbsp;Ralf points out that a discussion about
the future of release management for numpy, and whether the numpy
community would be happy with Ondrej continuing to work in this capacity
via&amp;nbsp;Numfocus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pydata-sv"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PyData&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leah mentioned that Fernando will be a keynote speaker Andy &amp;nbsp;and Anthony are
heavily involved with the organization of this year’s there and that Anthony
will run a tutorial on PyTables.  There’s also going to be a PyCon Booth,
Jarrod can’t make it but Andy will let us know soon if he can. &amp;nbsp;Fernando will
go to the NumFocus booth a&amp;nbsp;little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="miriam-sierig"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Miriam&amp;nbsp;Sierig&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The check for Miriam Sierig cleared and now all donations go directly to her on
the website. &amp;nbsp;The final amount collected by NumFocus, between the creation of
the Fund on August 29 2012 and Dec 31 2012 was&amp;nbsp;$91,500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>January 7, 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board-meeting-minutes2013-01-30.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-01-30:board-meeting-minutes2013-01-30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Participating&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leah Silen, Fernando Perez, Emmanuelle Gouillart, Andy R. Terrel,
Anthony Scopatz, Jarrod Millman, Ralf Gommers, Prabhu&amp;nbsp;Ramachandran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Not&amp;nbsp;attending&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Travis&amp;nbsp;Oliphant,&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="treasurers-report"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Treasurer’s&amp;nbsp;Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax filing situation: for 2012 we’ll need to do some paperwork related to
to taxes. &amp;nbsp;Anthony proposes contacting someone who can help with this;
he will inquire about the cost. &amp;nbsp;Leah mentions that NumFOCUS has joined
a non-profit support organization that could also provide information on
this matter. &amp;nbsp;Both Anthony and Leah will follow up with their contacts
to find out how to best&amp;nbsp;proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="approval-of-prior-minutes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Approval of Prior&amp;nbsp;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minutes from the previous meeting have been&amp;nbsp;accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="old-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approval of the appraisal of the domain was recorded, Leah will now take
care of having the appraisal&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teams:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fernando will finish up the team organization document, some teams were
merged from the previous&amp;nbsp;organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brochure: Emmanuelle asks for the sources for the brochure document so
she can translate it to French. &amp;nbsp;Leah will put the source file on the
shared folder so others can edit it as well and for Emanuelle to&amp;nbsp;translate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emanuelle just created a Twitter account for NumFOCUS; Andy asks about
password management, to which Jarrod proposes setting up a KeePassX
shared password file, which Jarrod will set up for&amp;nbsp;everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.&amp;nbsp;Discussion of adding Didrik Pinte to the Board as an official representative
from Enthought.  Fernando proposed to table the discussion until next meeting
to give Travis a chance to express his opinion, as he had mentioned by email
some thoughts on this but is not present today. &amp;nbsp;Ralf noted that the bylaws may
need amending for even/odd and more than 9 board members.  &amp;nbsp;Leah indicated this
can be done by simple vote during a board&amp;nbsp;meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.&amp;nbsp;Christoph Deil’s suggestion on a Mac for continuous integration.  The team
led by Jarrod and Ralf will work with Christoph to get the details of his
proposal and will work with him&amp;nbsp;further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.&amp;nbsp;Sloan Foundation: how it could help NumFOCUS. &amp;nbsp;Leah has had some brief email
exchanges already with Josh Greenberg, and will follow up further the
discussion with Jarrod and Andy who will take point on this&amp;nbsp;item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="action-items"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Action&amp;nbsp;Items:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KeePassX/dropbox -&amp;nbsp;jarrod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leah: set up emails going to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info&amp;#64;numfocus"&gt;info&amp;#64;numfocus&lt;/a&gt; so they go to&amp;nbsp;everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christoph Deil &amp;gt;&amp;gt; pointed to Jarrod and&amp;nbsp;Ralf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sloan follow-up - Jarrod/Andy &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Fernando can&amp;nbsp;help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leah will follow-up w/ Sloan and introduce Jarrod and&amp;nbsp;Andy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>January 21, 2013</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/board-meeting-minutes2013-01-21.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2013-01-21:board-meeting-minutes2013-01-21.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="participating"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Participating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leah Silen, Travis Oliphant, Anthony Scopatz, Ralf Gommers, Jarrod
Millman, Prabhu&amp;nbsp;Ramachandran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="not-attending"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not&amp;nbsp;Attending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fernando Perez, Emmanuelle Gouillart, Andy R. Terrel, Perry&amp;nbsp;Greenfield&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="approval-of-prior-minutes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Approval of Prior&amp;nbsp;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes look fine, and are&amp;nbsp;approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="old-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sloan&amp;nbsp;Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis mentioned that Sloan may be interested in providing seed funding
for the technical fellowships. &amp;nbsp;The idea being that once it is started,
it will be easier to get additional funding to continue it from
industry. &amp;nbsp;Ralf and Jarrod will contact Sloan to make a small initial
proposal with maybe funding for around 1 mentor and 1-2&amp;nbsp;fellowships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchase of a Mac for Christoph&amp;nbsp;Deil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided to host in a co-location facility. Ralf will follow-up with
Anthony to make this&amp;nbsp;happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didrik&amp;nbsp;Pinte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarrod will take an off-line inventory about whether we should increase
the size of the board, change members, or wait a bit longer before
revisiting the&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; sponsor booth and two passes. &amp;nbsp;Jarrod will try to help
man the booth on March 15-17. &amp;nbsp;We will organize a BoF and possibly an
in-person board&amp;nbsp;meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="team-reports"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team&amp;nbsp;Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundraising&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicity/Promotion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grants/Fellowships&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No reports&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-business"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New&amp;nbsp;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boot Camp for Women in Science and&amp;nbsp;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General interest, so Travis will contact Greg Wilson to get a specific proposal
for the board to&amp;nbsp;consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyGotham –&amp;nbsp;Travis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General concern about this not being focused on scientific programming. We
could try to organize a scientific track.  Non-Python scientifically-oriented
conferences may be more interesting than general Python&amp;nbsp;conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;PyData&amp;nbsp;sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis described that PyData proceeds will go to NumFocus. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The PyData
site would like to advertise this&amp;nbsp;fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For informational purposes, Continuum defines proceeds as money earned
from ticket sales and sponsorships beyond fixed costs (venue, website,
food, etc.) plus the travel of Leah and other community conference
organizers and participants (keynotes, speakers, etc.) to the
conference. &amp;nbsp;I need to check on this, but I believe the ticket sale
costs are set up to basically break even with about 2 sponsors and a
full conference. All of this is subject to change as the ability for
Continuum to under-write the conference&amp;nbsp;varies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just an example. &amp;nbsp;Other companies who under-write conferences
may have different metrics and approaches for determining proceeds. &amp;nbsp;We
should be willing to engage with as many people as possible at this
point. &amp;nbsp;Conferences can be a useful source of revenue for NumFOCUS as
long as they have significant&amp;nbsp;sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf, Jarrod, and Anthony expressed concern that conferences can also
have significant cost and NumFOCUS should be very careful before
agreeing to under-write a conference&amp;nbsp;itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="next-meeting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next&amp;nbsp;Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
February 4, 2013&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Software Distributions</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/software-distributions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-21T17:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Scopatz</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-12-21:software-distributions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following are software distributions which may aid in performing
computational science&amp;nbsp;tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.enthought.com/products/epd.php"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EPD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from&amp;nbsp;Enthought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://store.continuum.io/cshop/anaconda"&gt;Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; from Continuum&amp;nbsp;Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sagemath.org"&gt;Sage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pyzo.org/"&gt;Pyzo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pythonxy.com/"&gt;Python(x,y)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/winpython/"&gt;WinPython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.activestate.com/activepython"&gt;ActivePython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unofficial &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/"&gt;Windows Binaries&lt;/a&gt; for Python Extension&amp;nbsp;Packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this list is purely informational and &amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS does
not officially support or prefer any distribution. &amp;nbsp;If you would like to
see a distribution added to this list, please &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/contact-4/"&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>John Hunter Memorial Fund</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/johnhunter.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-28T23:29:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Travis</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-08-28:johnhunter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="John Hunter" class="align-right" src="static/images/John-hunter-crop-2.jpg" style="height: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hunter, author of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://matplotlib.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;, founding board
member of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org"&gt;NumFOCUS&lt;/a&gt;, husband to Miriam, and father to three daughters:
Clara, Ava, and Rahel, was diagnosed with cancer in late July 2012 after
returning from his keynote &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e3lTby5RI54&amp;amp;noredirect=1"&gt;address at SciPy&lt;/a&gt; in Austin, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TX&lt;/span&gt;. He passed
away on August 28th from complications arising from necessary cancer
treatment. See the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/pydata/FpwXp3sX6N8/mxopkZ1PkBQJ"&gt;announcement email&lt;/a&gt; by his good friend, Fernando&amp;nbsp;Perez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John has given so much to all of us in the Python community, now is our
time to give something back to his family by providing for the education
and support of his children. We have setup the John Hunter Memorial Fund
to provide a mechanism for individuals and companies who have
appreciated John&amp;#8217;s work, to give back to him by ensuring that his
children have funds available for their&amp;nbsp;education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linuxfr.org/news/deces-de-john-hunter-createur-de-matplotlib"&gt;View French&amp;nbsp;translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donations are gifts to Miriam and her girls. They will be used for the
care and education of Clara, Ava, and Rahel. As of A PayPal account has
been set up so that you may give to John&amp;#8217;s family directly. You may also
send a check directly to the family made out to Miriam Sierig and mailed
to the address below. &amp;nbsp;Thank you for your&amp;nbsp;generosity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PayPal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden"
        name="cmd"
        value="_s-xclick" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden"
       name="hosted_button_id"
       value="AY7E6Q8Z4A63J" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input type="image"
       alt="PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!" name="submit"
       src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donateCC_LG.gif" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif"
      width="1"
      height="1"
      border="0"/&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Miriam Sierig
953 E Hyde Park Blvd #2
Chicago, IL 60615
&lt;/pre&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Helpful Links</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/helpful-links.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-13T17:29:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-03-13:helpful-links.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scipy-central.org/"&gt;http://scipy-central.org/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;A collection of&amp;nbsp;code snippets, modules and
links for&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;solving scientific problems&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scipy.org/"&gt;SciPy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and related Python&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scicomp.stackexchange.com/"&gt;http://scicomp.stackexchange.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;This is a great place to ask questions
about scientific computing with NumPy, SciPy, and other related&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scipy.org"&gt;http://scipy.org&lt;/a&gt; - Home page of SciPy&amp;nbsp;project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.enthought.com/repo/free/"&gt;http://www.enthought.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Free Enthought Python&amp;nbsp;Distribution&amp;nbsp;Download&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://store.continuum.io/cshop/anaconda"&gt;https://store.continuum.io/cshop/anaconda&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Anaconda &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CE&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Download&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/pythonxy/wiki/Downloads?tm=2"&gt;http://code.google.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Python &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XY&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Download&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/python"&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Stack Overflow Python&amp;nbsp;Questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project&amp;nbsp;repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/numpy/numpy"&gt;NumPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/scipy/scipy"&gt;Scipy&amp;nbsp;repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib"&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/ipython/ipython"&gt;IPython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/sympy/sympy"&gt;SymPy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cython/cython"&gt;Cython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/pydata/pandas"&gt;pandas&amp;nbsp;repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pytables.github.com/"&gt;PyTables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/stefanv/scikits.image"&gt;scikits-image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/scikit-learn/scikit-learn"&gt;scikits-learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/statsmodels/statsmodels"&gt;scikits-statsmodels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/spyderlib/source/checkout"&gt;spyder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/Theano/Theano"&gt;theano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project mailing lists and&amp;nbsp;discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.scipy.org/mailman/listinfo/numpy-discussion"&gt;NumPy&amp;nbsp;discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dir.gmane.org/gmane.comp.python.scientific.user"&gt;Scipy&amp;nbsp;user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dir.gmane.org/gmane.comp.python.scientific.devel"&gt;Scipy&amp;nbsp;dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sourceforge.net/mail/?group_id=80706"&gt;matplotlib&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.scipy.org/mailman/listinfo/ipython-user"&gt;Ipython&amp;nbsp;user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.scipy.org/mailman/listinfo/ipython-dev"&gt;Ipython&amp;nbsp;dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/sympy"&gt;SymPy&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/cython-users"&gt;Cython&amp;nbsp;user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/cython-devel"&gt;Cython&amp;nbsp;dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/pydata"&gt;pandas&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/pytables-users"&gt;PyTables&amp;nbsp;user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/scikits-image"&gt;scikits-image&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/scikit-learn-general"&gt;scikits-learn&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/pystatsmodels"&gt;scikits-statsmodels&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/spyderlib"&gt;spyder&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/theano-users"&gt;theano&amp;nbsp;user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/theano-dev"&gt;theano&amp;nbsp;dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Scientific Computing with Python</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/scientific-computing-with-python.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T16:31:00+01:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:scientific-computing-with-python.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="http://gallery.mailchimp.com/e91b4574d5d1709a9dc4f7ab7/images/scipy_logo_shiny_blue_no_reflec.png" src="http://gallery.mailchimp.com/e91b4574d5d1709a9dc4f7ab7/images/scipy_logo_shiny_blue_no_reflec.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://conference.scipy.org/scipy2013/"&gt;SciPy&lt;/a&gt; will be June 24-29, 2013 in Austin,&amp;nbsp;Texax&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Women in Science and Engineering Boot Camp</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/women-in-science-and-engineering-boot-camp.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T16:31:00+01:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:women-in-science-and-engineering-boot-camp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Due in part to a generous donation made by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J.P.&lt;/span&gt; Morgan to NumFOCUS, we are
pleased to announce that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numfocus.org/"&gt;NumFOCUS&lt;/a&gt; will be collaborating with &lt;a class="reference external" href="software-carpentry.org"&gt;Software Carpentry&lt;/a&gt;
to host a series of  boot camps to offer training for women in technology. The
first, a boot camp for 120 women in science and engineering, will be held at
the Microsoft Research Center in Cambridge, Massachusetts on June&amp;nbsp;24-25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this event is to help scientists and engineers become more
productive by teaching them basic computing skills like program design, version
control, testing, and task automation. In this two-day boot camp, short
tutorials will alternate with hands-on practical exercises.
The boot camp is open to female graduate students, post-docs, faculty members,
staff scientists, or their equivalent in science, engineering, medicine, or a
related field in academia, industry, or the public and non-profit&amp;nbsp;sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sponsors"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J.P.&amp;nbsp;Morgan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alfred P. Sloan&amp;nbsp;Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla&amp;nbsp;Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Corporation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;King Abdullah University of Science and&amp;nbsp;Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Software&amp;nbsp;Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Donate</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/donatejoin.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T15:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:donatejoin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="NumFOCUS" src="static/images/nf-web-with-tag.jpg" style="height: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS supports and promotes world-class, innovative, open source
scientific software. Most individual projects, even the wildly
successful ones, find the overhead of a non-profit to be too large for
their community to bear. NumFOCUS provides a critical service as an
umbrella organization which removes the burden from the projects
themselves to raise&amp;nbsp;money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money donated through NumFOCUS goes to sponsor things&amp;nbsp;like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding sprints (food and&amp;nbsp;travel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical fellowships (sponsored students and mentors to work on&amp;nbsp;code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equipment grants (to developers and&amp;nbsp;projects)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference attendance for students (to PyData, SciPy, and other&amp;nbsp;conferences)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fees for continuous integration and other software engineering&amp;nbsp;tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&amp;nbsp;development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web-page hosting and bandwidth fees for&amp;nbsp;projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NumFOCUS aims to ensure that money is available to keep projects in the
scientific Python stack funded and available. So if you find value in
these tools and have always wanted to give back, donating to NumFOCUS
gives you a way of supporting either a specific project of your choice
or all of these great codes at&amp;nbsp;once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NumFOCUS has received 501(c)3 status as a public charity in the
United&amp;nbsp;States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to give. We have tried to make it as simple as
possible to donate to NumFOCUS. You can use any of the following payment&amp;nbsp;providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PayPal&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;nbsp;(2.90% + $0.30 /&amp;nbsp;transaction)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post"&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" name="cmd" value="_s-xclick"/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" name="hosted_button_id" value="HK2N4RM5NMDZC"/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;input type="image"
         src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donateCC_LG.gif"
         border="0"
         name="submit"
         alt="PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!"/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=""
        border="0"
        src="https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif"
        width="1"
        height="1"/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Checkout&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;nbsp;(2.90% + $0.30 /&amp;nbsp;transaction)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="1%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td align="right" nowrap="nowrap" width="1%"&gt;$
    &lt;input id="item_price_1" type="text" name="item_price_1" value="64.00" size="6" /&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td align="left" width="1%"&gt;
    &lt;input type="image" src="https://checkout.google.com/buttons/donateNow.gif?merchant_id=112611646391039&amp;amp;w=115&amp;amp;h=50&amp;amp;style=white&amp;amp;variant=text&amp;amp;loc=en_US" alt="Donate" /&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WePay&lt;/strong&gt; - (2.90% + $0.30 /&amp;nbsp;transaction)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(custom&amp;nbsp;amount)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$512.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$256.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$128.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$64.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$32.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wepay.com/donations/78917"&gt;Donate&amp;nbsp;$16.00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dwolla&lt;/strong&gt; - ($0.25 / transaction) &amp;#8212; No credit cards and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; banks&amp;nbsp;only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;input onclick="location.href='https://www.dwolla.com/hub/numfocus?memo=General%20Fund';"
       type="image"
       src="https://www.dwolla.com/content/images/btn-donate-with-dwolla.png" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checks&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Make payable to&amp;nbsp;NumFOCUS and mail&amp;nbsp;to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
NumFOCUS
P.O. Box 90596
Austin, TX 78709
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your personal contribution is greatly&amp;nbsp;appreciated!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Tokyo SciPy</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/tokyo-scipy2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T15:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:tokyo-scipy2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="|filename|/images/Tokyo-SciPy.jpg" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/Tokyo-SciPy.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman of NumFOCUS&amp;#8217; Board of Director&amp;#8217;s,Travis Oliphant, spoke at the
March meeting of Tokyo SciPy via live webcast.&amp;nbsp; Topics he covered
included the history of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://scipy.org/"&gt;SciPy&lt;/a&gt;, where&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://numpy.org/"&gt;NumPy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;should go next,
and Numba. &amp;nbsp;Questions were asked regarding sparse matrix integration
with NumPy, and&amp;nbsp;packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo SciPy member, Syoyo, gave Travis the link to his code for
simulating smoke, &amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/smoke3d/"&gt;http://code.google.com/p/smoke3d/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps at
some point, Syoyo will be able to make that code fast using&amp;nbsp;Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a late night, due to the fourteen hour time difference between
Austin and Tokyo, Travis spoke for over an hour.&amp;nbsp; He later stated, “…it
was nice to see that SciPy and NumPy have a user community in&amp;nbsp;Japan.”&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>EuroSciPy 2012</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/euroscipy-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T15:46:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:euroscipy-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;#8217;s EuroSciPy conference will be held
in&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Brussels&lt;/strong&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;August 23-27&lt;/strong&gt;, at the Université Libre de
Bruxelles (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ULB&lt;/span&gt;, Solbosch Campus). &amp;nbsp;This Euroscipy meeting will be the
5th edition of this cross-disciplinary gathering, focused on the use and
development of the Python language in scientific research and&amp;nbsp;industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Python in Astronomy</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/python-in-astronomy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:python-in-astronomy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="|filename|/images/sn-blackholes.jpg" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/sn-blackholes.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 28 March, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;’s Swift satellite&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2011/04/star-eating-black-hole-may-be-pr.html?ref=hp"&gt;observed a flash of gamma rays
brighter than anything astronomers had seen before&lt;/a&gt;. It soon became
evident that the event wasn’t a typical gamma ray burst, an emission of
high-energy radiation that often accompanies a supernova explosion. The
flash didn’t die out but was sustained for weeks, and although it has
faded in intensity, it is still going strong 2½ months later. Two papers
published online today in&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;provide an explanation for this
luminous surprise. The flare is in fact&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/abstract/science.1207143"&gt;a high-energy jet of
radiation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;produced by a star falling into a black hole at the center
of a galaxy 4 billion light-years away. The reason the flare is so
bright is that the jet is pointed straight in the direction of Earth.
And it’s sustained because &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/abstract/science.1207150"&gt;the black hole is consuming the star
gradually&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s because as the black hole rips the star apart, the
mass swirls around like water going down a drain, and this swirling
process releases a lot of energy,” says Joshua Bloom, an astronomer at
the University of California, Berkeley, and lead author of one of the
two papers. Bloom expects the flare to fade out over the next&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2011/06/scienceshot-powerful-jet-being.html?ref=hp"&gt;http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2011/06/scienceshot-powerful-jet-being.html?ref=hp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by&amp;nbsp;Yudhijit Bhattacharjee&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;16 June 2011, 2:00&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For related story and photo,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://discovermagazine.com/2012/jan-feb/14"&gt;http://discovermagazine.com/2012/jan-feb/14&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Circuitscape Protects Endangered Species Using PyAMG</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/python-pyamg.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leah</name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2012-02-25:python-pyamg.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="|filename|/images/zimmer_gene_circuit_500px.jpg" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/zimmer_gene_circuit_500px.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists map the &amp;#8220;current&amp;#8221; of mountain lions moving between mountain ranges. Blue shows areas of low current density, which are expected to have low densities of dispersing mountain lions; yellow designates movement bottlenecks, which are most vulnerable to habitat destruction. Destroying high-flow habitat can isolate populations and endanger their survival.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Image:&amp;nbsp;Brad McRae and Brett&amp;nbsp;Dickson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/pyamg/"&gt;PyAMG&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source numerical package of multigrid and Krylov
solvers for sparse matrices in Python.&amp;nbsp; One of the biggest users of
PyAMG is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.circuitscape.org/Circuitscape/Welcome.html"&gt;Circuitscape&lt;/a&gt;. This open-source software program borrows
algorithms from electronic circuit theory to predict patterns of
movement, gene flow, and genetic differentiation among plant and animal
populations in heterogeneous landscapes.&amp;nbsp; Circuit theory complements
least-cost path approaches because it considers effects of all possible
pathways across a landscape&amp;nbsp;simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.circuitscape.org/Circuitscape/Welcome.html"&gt;Circuitscape&lt;/a&gt; was written by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nceas.ucsb.edu/~mcrae/Welcome.html"&gt;Brad McRae&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.allthingshpc.org/"&gt;Viral Shah&lt;/a&gt;.
Brad&amp;nbsp;is an Ecologist with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://waconservation.org/"&gt;The Nature Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle.&amp;nbsp; He
works on habitat connectivity conservation, climate change, and
landscape genetics. &amp;nbsp;Viral&amp;nbsp;is a Senior Scientist with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.interactivesupercomputing.com/"&gt;Interactive
Supercomputing&lt;/a&gt; and a Visiting Scientist at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ucsb.edu/"&gt;University of
California, Santa Barbara.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;He develops systems for scientific
computing for work and for&amp;nbsp;fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For additional information on&amp;nbsp;`Circuitscape`_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors presentation at SciPy 2008:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.circuitscape.org/Circuitscape/Pubs_files/Shah_McRae_Circuitscape_Python_Scipy08.pdf"&gt;http://www.circuitscape.org/Circuitscape/Pubs_files/Shah_McRae_Circuitscape_Python_Scipy08.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conservation Magazine:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.conservationmagazine.org/articles/v9n1/circuitous-routes/"&gt;Circuitous Routes: Circuit Theory Guides
Wildlife Corridor Design by Eric&amp;nbsp;Wagner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired Magazine:&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wired.com/science/planetearth/news/2007/12/dissection_1210"&gt;Scientist Employs &amp;#8216;Circuit Theory&amp;#8217; to Protect Endangered Species by Carl&amp;nbsp;Zimmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Convergence Magazine:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://convergence.ucsb.edu/article/where-wild-things-are"&gt;Where the Wild Things Are by Anna&amp;nbsp;Davison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earthtimes.org&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.earthtimes.org/articles/show/news_press_release,90605.shtml"&gt;Where Mountain Lions Roam: Star-P Helps Decipher
Threatened Wildlife&amp;nbsp;Migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Continuum Analytics</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/continuum-analytics.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,2010-01-01:continuum-analytics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://continuum.io"&gt;&lt;img alt="Continuum Analytics" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/continuum_500px_w_logo.png" style="height: 100px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by the creators of NumPy, SciPy, and Chaco, Continuum offers
Python-based tools and consulting services for the analysis, management and
visualization of big data. Continuum’s premier Python distribution, Anaconda,
performs high-performance, large data analysis, including statistics, machine
learning, and distributed computing. Wakari, Continuum’s newest product, is an
online cloud-based Python analytics environment for easy sharing of code,
visualizations, IPython Notebooks, data sets and derived data products.
Cloud-hosted or installed internally, Wakari allows users to harness
Continuum’s full product set, including Anaconda and enterprise-supported
Python, from their&amp;nbsp;browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Gold Level"></category></entry><entry><title>J. P. Morgan</title><link href="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/j-p-morgan.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>1900-01-01T00:00:00+00:09</updated><author><name></name></author><id>tag:numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org,1900-01-01:j-p-morgan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jpmorgan.com"&gt;&lt;img alt="J. P. Morgan" src="http://numfocus.github.io/numfocus.org/static/images/Logo2008_JPM_D_Black.png" style="height: 100px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;J.P.&lt;/span&gt; Morgan is a leader in financial services, offering solutions to clients in
more than 100 countries with one of the most comprehensive global product
platforms available. We have been helping our clients to do business and manage
their wealth for more than 200 years. Our business has been built upon our core
principle of putting our clients’ interests&amp;nbsp;first.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Platinum Level"></category></entry></feed>